<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Owais Lone</title>
    <link>https://owais.lone.pw/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Owais Lone</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 May 2015 00:31:14 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://owais.lone.pw/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Webpack transparently with Django &#43; hot reloading React components as a bonus</title>
      <link>https://owais.lone.pw/blog/webpack-plus-reactjs-and-django/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2015 00:31:14 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owais.lone.pw/blog/webpack-plus-reactjs-and-django/</guid>
      <description>If you don&#39;t already know webpack, you&#39;ve some catching up to do.
 Webpack is a module bundler that bundles javascript and other assets for the browser. It works really well for applications and javascript libraries and is very simple frontend build tool.
- Kent C. Dodds - https://egghead.io/lessons/javascript-intro-to-webpack&amp;lt;/small&amp;gt;
 Objectives and reasoning We&#39;ll be setting up webpack and keeping it decoupled from django&#39;s staticfiles system. Read my earlier postexplaining why we&#39;ll be handling things this way and not integrating with staticfiles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s modernize the way we handle frontend code with Django</title>
      <link>https://owais.lone.pw/blog/modern-frontends-with-django/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2015 02:03:50 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owais.lone.pw/blog/modern-frontends-with-django/</guid>
      <description>The problem Django is great but it&#39;s frontend toolchain is stuck in the past. Imagine if someone told you to copy all your python module dependencies in your source tree and import them from there. Unthinkable, right? We&#39;ve pip and virtualenv for that. We also have npm and bower for frontend packages but we still choose to manage frontend packages manually or write very complex wrappers over javascript tools so that we only have to deal with Python.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remember The Rhythm</title>
      <link>https://owais.lone.pw/blog/remember-the-rhythm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2011 05:30:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owais.lone.pw/blog/remember-the-rhythm/</guid>
      <description>I recently switched to Rhythmbox from Banshee and I&#39;m loving it. It&#39;s fast, loads up almost instantly, doesn&#39;t consume as much resources as Bansee and doesn&#39;t crash after every 3 songs. I do miss some features that Banshee had though like remembering the last playing song. So, I created a plugin for rhythmbox just to do that. It remembers the last playing entry (song, radio station, podcast, etc), playback time, browser filters (genre, artist and album) and playlists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banshee 2 in Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://owais.lone.pw/blog/banshee-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2011 05:30:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owais.lone.pw/blog/banshee-2/</guid>
      <description>Just noticed a small but nice change in Banshee 2. Usually, our music players minimize to system tray when closing the main window so that the music keeps playing in the background. We have to manually look for a quit function in order to entirely close the app or pause the music and let the app live in memory and consume cpu cycles. Banshee 2.0 has no quit function per se.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Update on GmailWatcher</title>
      <link>https://owais.lone.pw/blog/update-gmailwatcher/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2010 05:30:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owais.lone.pw/blog/update-gmailwatcher/</guid>
      <description>In case you don&#39;t already know, GmailWatcher is a Gmail notifier specifically designed for the Ubuntu Operating System. It relies heavily on Ubuntu specific packages like MeMenu, Notifications, DesktopCouch but I&#39;m planning a stock Gnome version also so that people on Fedora, Suse and other rocking distribution can use it too.
Features  Multiple Accounts Google Apps support Secure password storage using Gnome-Keyring Themable unread emails page Preferences sync using U1  Right now, my target is to make it stable/usable enough in time for Maverick.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From TC 90 to Python</title>
      <link>https://owais.lone.pw/blog/tc-90-python-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2010 05:30:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owais.lone.pw/blog/tc-90-python-27/</guid>
      <description>This Saturday I&#39;ll be delivering a workshop on the Python programming language in my college. Our university has an age old course for Computer Engineering. C is the introductory language and is taught using the Turbo C compiler from the 90s, VB 6 is considered the best way to make GIUs. It&#39;s time to introduce my friends to 2010 in Computer Science.
If this goes well, Django or PyGTK will be next.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing GmailWatcher</title>
      <link>https://owais.lone.pw/blog/gmail-watcher/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2010 05:30:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owais.lone.pw/blog/gmail-watcher/</guid>
      <description>In case you don&#39;t already know, GmailWatcher is a Gmail notifier specifically designed for the Ubuntu Operating System. It relies heavily on Ubuntu specific packages like MeMenu, Notifications, DesktopCouch but I&#39;m planning a stock Gnome version also so that people on Fedora, Suse and other rocking distribution can use it too.
Features  Multiple Accounts Google Apps support Secure password storage using Gnome-Keyring Themable unread emails page Preferences sync using U1  Right now, my target is to make it stable/usable enough in time for Maverick.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kargil</title>
      <link>https://owais.lone.pw/blog/kargil/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2010 05:30:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owais.lone.pw/blog/kargil/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOSS Kashmir</title>
      <link>https://owais.lone.pw/blog/foss-kashmir/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2010 05:30:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owais.lone.pw/blog/foss-kashmir/</guid>
      <description>Finally Mir Nazim has kicked off the Kashmir FOSS mailing list. Things should only soar from here on. Really excited. Check http://fosskashmir.appspot.com. </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>